Ashley Yarbrough

Canton, TX | 512-577-2988 | AshleyY1065@gmail.com | linkedin.com/devashleyyarbrough | ashleyyarbrough.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack developer with experience in building and deploying web applications. Strong proficiency in HTML, JavaScript, Python, and SQL. Proven experience in working with international teams and diverse cultures, with a passion for creating intuitive and user-friendly solutions. Skilled in Agile methodologies, Git and version control, and modern web development frameworks. Committed to staying up-to-date with the latest industry trends and technologies. Fluent in English and Spanish.

## **SKILLS**

Front End: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, TypeScript, React Native, Redux.js, Flask, Django, jQuery, SASS Back End: Python, SQL, NodeJS, PostgreSQL, Express.js, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud, Azure Developer Tools: Git, Bash, Docker, Kubernetes, VS Code, GitHub

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Back End, SQL, and DevOps with Python Front End Web and Mobile Development Nucamp Coding Bootcamp Nucamp Coding Bootcamp

Texas State University San Marcos, TX - BA Psychology & BA Spanish

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Freelance**Web Developer

Canton, Texas
Dec 2021 - Present

- Designed & developed multiple mobile-first websites for small businesses utilizing responsive design with HTML, CSS, & JavaScript to ensure optimal user experience and cross-browser compatibility on all devices. Worked with clients to understand their needs and requirements, and delivered high-quality solutions within tight deadlines.
- Troubleshot existing codebase for customers, using React to create more concise code with reusable components, reducing the loading time, enhancing scalability, and improving UX scores.
- Optimized SEO architectures across 5 sites, resulting in a 15% increase in web traffic and an 11% increase in leads.

Elfore - Lead English Instructor Gangnam SLP - English Instructor Seoul, South Korea Jun 2017 - Mar 2020 Jul 2015 - Mar 2017

- Led and managed a team of teachers while implementing assessment and evaluation systems to measure student progress and provide feedback for ongoing improvement.
- Facilitated 15 classroom hours of weekly instruction for 130 students, resulting in a 90% success rate on standardized English tests.
- Organized 102 weekly events with directors & teachers for over 300 students, increasing involvement by 75%.
- Contributed to a collaborative team environment by effectively communicating and working closely with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals and deadlines.
- Created individualized learning programs to ensure 130+ students grasped concepts, helped improved average scores on English proficiency exams by 20%.
- Developed & administered 2 theater instruction programs to 15 students aged 7-12, culminating in a full-length play production.

# **PROJECTS**

Instagram Database Clone

[ https://tinyurl.com/igdbclone ]

- SQL project that duplicates the database structure of Instagram and is used to perform data analysis to extract insights for real-world business-related questions and scenarios.
- This project can be valuable for businesses looking to understand their target audience and make informed decisions based on data.

City Locations

[ https://tinyurl.com/cityloc ]

- A Django app written in Python that can be used to include city locations easily.
- This efficient module can be added to any existing project, which optimizes scalability.

NuCamp

[ https://tinyurl.com/48bsu7h8]

- Responsive camping site built with Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, & JavaScript.
- A lightweight website used to discover and reserve campsites.

Portfolio

[ ashleyyarbrough.com ]

- An efficient portfolio site where these and other projects are showcased using React, Typescript, HTML, & CSS.
- Connects LinkedIn, GitHub, contact information, and a resume pdf all in one place